cosmetix.in 2012-12-14

# Privacy Policy - Cosmetix.in

## **Privacy Policy**

 **We respect your privacy. This Privacy Policy provides succinctly the manner your data is collected and used by cosmetix.in. You are  advised to please read the Privacy Policy carefully. By accessing the services provided by cosmetix.in you agree to the collection and use of your data by cosmetix.in in the manner provided in this Privacy Policy.**

 **What information is, or may be, collected from you?**

We will automatically receive and collect certain anonymous information in standard usage logs through our Web server, including 

  * computer-identification information obtained from "cookies," sent to your browser from a web server cookie stored on your hard drive
  * an IP address, assigned to the computer through which you access our service
  * the type of computer you're using
  * the type of web browser you're using

We may collect the following personally identifiable information about you:

  * name including first and last name
  * alternate email address
  * mobile phone number and contact details
  * ZIP/Postal code
  * financial information (like account or credit card numbers); and
  * opinions of features on our websites.
  * Other information as per our registration process

We may also collect the following information:

  * about the pages you visit/access
  * the links you click on our site
  * the number of times you access the page
  * the number of times you have shopped on our web site

You can terminate your account at any time.

 **Who collects the information?**

We will collect anonymous traffic information from you when you visit our site. We will collect personally identifiable information about you only as part of a voluntary registration process, on-line survey, or contest or any combination thereof. 

**How is the information used?**

We use your personal information to:

  * help us provide personalized features to tailor our sites to your interest
  * to get in touch with you when necessary
  * to provide the services requested by you
  * to preserve social history as governed by existing law or policy

We use contact information internally to:

  * direct our efforts for product improvement
  * contact you as a survey respondent
  * notify you when the stock of the product in your wishlist is available
  * notify you if you win any contest; and
  * send you promotional materials from our contest sponsors or advertisers

Generally, we use anonymous traffic information to:

  * remind us of who you are in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service from both an advertising and an editorial perspective; 
  * recognize your access privileges to our Websites
  * track your entries in some of our promotions, sweepstakes and contests
  * make sure that you don't see the same ad repeatedly
  * help diagnose problems with our server
  * administer our websites,
  * track your session so that we can understand better how people use our sites 

**With whom will your information be shared?**

We will not use your financial information for any purpose other than to complete a payment transaction with you.

We do not rent, sell or share your personal information and we will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information to third parties unless

  * we have your permission to provide products or services you've requested 
  * to help, investigate, prevent or take action regarding unlawful and illegal activities,
  * suspected fraud, potential threat to the safety or security of any person, violations of cosmetix.in's terms of use or to defend against legal claims
  * Special circumstances such as compliance with subpoenas, court orders, requests/order, notices from legal authorities or law enforcement agencies requiring such disclosure 

**What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of your information?**

You may change your interests at any time and may opt-in or opt-out of any marketing / promotional / newsletters mailings. 

Upon request, we will remove/block your personally identifiable information from our database, thereby canceling your registration.

If we plan to use your personally identifiable information for any commercial purposes, we will notify you at the time we collect that information and allow you to opt-out of having your information used for those purposes. 

**What security procedures are in place to protect information from loss, misuse or alteration?**

To protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control, we have in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures. Our servers are accessible only to authorized personnel and your information is shared with respective personnel on need to know basis to complete the transaction and to provide the services requested by you. 

Although we will endeavor to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information by providing a secure connection for pages having your confidential information, transmissions made by means of the Internet cannot be made absolutely secure. By using this site, you agree that we will have no liability for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties. 

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using [Contact Us form](https://cosmetix.in/contact-form.php) to support@cosmetix.in

 **Policy updates**

We reserve the right to change or update this policy at any time by placing a prominent notice on our site. Such changes shall be effective immediately upon posting to this site.
